cartermatt.com 2019-10-20

# Privacy Policy and Terms of Use - CarterMatt

## **Privacy Policy**

By reading and visiting the site, you offer explicit consent and understanding for the information stored below.

In visiting this site, your name and personal information will not be shared with any other organization or sold to any third party. We use cookies to manage data (which includes demographics and location for analytics) and to calculate browsing. We will not share this information or any other IP information in an attempt to exploit your identity, sell you any products, or barrage you with spam. If you do choose to provide your email address to subscribe to our newsletter, this information will not be shared or sold. The same goes for any search entries.

The only case in which any personal information (such as an IP address) may be shared is in the event of damaging or illegal activity. By reading content on the website, you  **consent  **to having your cookies stored. Search information will be tracked via analytics.

If there are any questions regarding data use or requests feel free to contact cartermattnews (at) gmail.com and you will receive a response within 72 hours.

## GDPR

CarterMatt is committed to safeguarding your privacy. Contact us at cartermattnews (at) gmail.com if you have any questions or problems regarding the use of your Personal Data and we will gladly assist you.

By using this site or/and our services, you consent to the Processing of your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy.  
This Privacy Policy is a part of our Terms and Conditions; by agreeing to Terms and Conditions you also agree to this Policy. In the event of collision of terms used in Terms and Conditions and Privacy Policy, the latter shall prevail.

We promise to follow the following data protection principles:

  * Processing is lawful, fair, transparent. Our Processing activities have lawful grounds. We always consider your rights before Processing Personal Data. We will provide you information regarding Processing upon request.
  * Processing is limited to the purpose. Our Processing activities fit the purpose for which Personal Data was gathered.
  * Processing is done with minimal data. We only gather and Process the minimal amount of Personal Data required for any purpose.
  * Processing is limited with a time period. We will not store your personal data for longer than needed.
  * We will do our best to ensure the accuracy of data.
  * We will do our best to ensure the integrity and confidentiality of data.

The Data Subject has the following rights:

  1. Right to information – meaning you have to right to know whether your Personal Data is being processed; what data is gathered, from where it is obtained and why and by whom it is processed.
  2. Right to access – meaning you have the right to access the data collected from/about you. This includes your right to request and obtain a copy of your Personal Data gathered.
  3. Right to rectification – meaning you have the right to request rectification or erasure of your Personal Data that is inaccurate or incomplete.
  4. Right to erasure – meaning in certain circumstances you can request for your Personal Data to be erased from our records.
  5. Right to restrict processing – meaning where certain conditions apply, you have the right to restrict the Processing of your Personal Data.
  6. Right to object to processing – meaning in certain cases you have the right to object to Processing of your Personal Data, for example in the case of direct marketing.
  7. Right to object to automated Processing – meaning you have the right to object to automated Processing, including profiling; and not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated Processing. This right you can exercise whenever there is an outcome of the profiling that produces legal effects concerning or significantly affecting you.
  8. Right to data portability – you have the right to obtain your Personal Data in a machine-readable format or if it is feasible, as a direct transfer from one Processor to another.
  9. Right to lodge a complaint – in the event that we refuse your request under the Rights of Access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. If you are not satisfied with the way your request has been handled please contact us.
  10. Right for the help of supervisory authority – meaning you have the right for the help of a supervisory authority and the right for other legal remedies such as claiming damages.
  11. Right to withdraw consent – you have the right withdraw any given consent for Processing of your Personal Data.

We do our best to keep your Personal Data safe.  We use safe protocols for communication and transferring data (such as HTTPS). We use anonymising and pseudonymising where suitable. We monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks.

Even though we try our best we can not guarantee the security of information. However, we promise to notify suitable authorities of data breaches. We will also notify you if there is a threat to your rights or interests. We will do everything we reasonably can to prevent security breaches and to assist authorities should any breaches occur.

### Children

We do not intend to collect or knowingly collect information from children. We do not target children with our services.

We use cookies and/or similar technologies to analyse customer behaviour, administer the website, track users’ movements, and to collect information about users. This is done in order to personalise and enhance your experience with us.

A cookie is a tiny text file stored on your computer. Cookies store information that is used to help make sites work. Only we can access the cookies created by our website. You can control your cookies at the browser level. Choosing to disable cookies may hinder your use of certain functions.

**We use cookies for the following purposes:**

  * Necessary cookies – these cookies are required for you to be able to use some important features on our website, such as logging in.
  * Functionality cookies – these cookies provide functionality that makes using our service more convenient and makes providing more personalized features possible.
  * Analytics cookies – these cookies are used to track the use and performance of our website and services
  * Advertising cookies – these cookies are used to deliver advertisements that are relevant to you and to your interests. In addition, they are used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement. They are usually placed to the website by advertising networks with the website operator’s permission. These cookies remember that you have visited a website and this information is shared with other organisations such as advertisers. Often targeting or advertising cookies will be linked to site functionality provided by the other organisation. Technology Partners in the field of advertising include Unruly Media, Index Exchange, Google, Inc., Disqus, and Zergnet. In visiting CarterMatt you consent to seeing advertising from these partners.

You can remove cookies stored in your computer via your browser settings. Alternatively, you can control some 3rd party cookies by using a privacy enhancement platform such as [optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/) or [youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/). For more information about cookies, visit [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

We use Google Analytics to measure traffic on our website. Google has their own Privacy Policy which you can review [here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245). If you’d like to opt out of tracking by Google Analytics, visit the [Google Analytics opt-out page](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

If you have any questions regarding Processing your Personal Data, your rights regarding your Personal Data or this Privacy Policy, contact our Data Protection OfficerMatt Carter at cartermattnews (at) gmail.com

Name: Matthew Carter Email: cartermattnews (at) gmail.com

Email: info@dataprotection.ie  
Phone: +353 57 868 4800

We reserve the right to make change to this Privacy Policy.  
Last modification was made November 14, 2018.

### More on Advertising / Personal Privacy

Cartermatt.com does provide advertisement opportunities to companies and there will be advertisements that are viewable on the site. These third party advertisements are not connected to the Cartermatt.com site and they are owned by the independent retailers. We do not endorse the merchandise sold and we do not take responsibility for any companies that advertise through our site. Any advertisements that you click on and subsequently purchase, you do at your own risk and we are not liable. We have no liability for any content or substance of third-party ads.

Vendors from third parties such as Google will use cookies to provide ads based on prior visits to the website. To use this, Google utilizes a DART cookie to facilitate their third-party program. If you would like to opt out of this cookie, please visit this [page](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).  You can also choose to opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies over at this [link](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Please do not post personal information about yourself on our site, no emails, phone numbers or mailing addresses. We are not held responsible for your actions if you choose to do so and we hold the right to remove this content if we find it posted on the site. Do not collect personal information about other users from this site, if you do please note that you will be held liable for those actions and could face criminal charges.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

### Plugin Use

Plugins including Sassy Social Share may work to track individual shares. However, no information from the user is obtained via such practice.

**Terms of Use**

All of the Terms of Use of this website must be agreed upon by you, the user and if this is not the case please do not use this site any further. If you do use this site you are agreeing to the Terms of Use set out by our legal team.

Our Terms of Use may be changed at any time without notice, but will always be updated and found in this section so please check back for updates as your continued use of this site will be an agreement to our updated Terms of Use.

You are using this site at your own risk. We are not responsible for any issues that may occur while you are using the site. Cartermatt.com does not accept any liability when it comes to any loss or damage resulting from the use of our site.

Although Cartermatt.com does not have a registration requirement when posting comments on the site, we do warn that the content of this site may not be suitable for children. If you are under 18 years of age and have not received consent from a parent, then please discontinue using this site. If you are using this site, we will have to assume that you are of legal age to accept the Terms of Use agreement of the site.

In addition, you shall not falsely publish, distribute, or exploit this web site (along with its accompanying code or data) on any platform for any purpose without prior written permission nor may any user attempt to edit or remove any content or coding on this site. All use of this site must be held in accordance of United States law alongside any local or state laws currently established. Site content cannot be lifted or plagiarized for any purpose.

CarterMatt.com does not accept any unsolicited content or stories or submissions. Any unsolicited content will not be reviewed and any content sent via post will be returned unopened.

If you have seen content on this site that you believe infringes on your copyright rights, please contact us at [info@cartermatt.com](mailto:info@cartermatt.com.com) so that we can address the issues.

**Copyright Policy**

All rights reserved to CarterMatt.com exclusively. No part of this publication may be reproduced, distributed, or transmitted in any form or by any means, including photocopying, recording, or other electronic or mechanical methods, without the prior written permission of the publisher, except in the case of brief quotations embodied in critical reviews and certain other noncommercial uses permitted by copyright law. For permission requests, write to the publisher (CarterMatt.com)

**Commenting Policy  
**  
Please be aware that the opinions posted by our users are not the opinions of the writers at Cartermatt.com. Comments that are spam, defamatory, name calling or threatening to fellow users will not be tolerated. Comments of such a nature will be removed from the site. Parents should be warned that the comments are not moderated constantly, and that children could stumble upon content they deem inappropriate.

Comments that are removed will not re-appear on the site. No user shall engage in any illegal activity or false impersonation in the comments section, and penalties for such actions will be determined by local and national laws. When it comes to self-promotion, we ask that you remember that the main purpose of comments are to facilitate a discussion. Comments that are solely designed to direct traffic elsewhere will be marked as spam. Do not share any personal contact information on any page.

We will not alter a comment unless there is swearing in it, but we reserve the right to remove any comment at any time without explanation. It is our sole discretion when it comes to whether or not a comment is removed. Know that we are not responsible for the content of comments on the site.

We conduct many polls on our site and we allow readers to vote multiple times. These polls are just for fun and we don’t allow defamatory, or threatening comments to other fans (or to any of the CarterMatt.com staff) on these polls or in the comment section.

Your email address may be stored with your comment, but will not be used for any purpose and will not be shown.

**Newsletter Policy**

In accordance with the anti-spamming law in Canada (and our own personal stance on spamming), we will never use someone’s email address without permission and add it to our weekly CarterMatt newsletter. The only way an email address will ever been added to receive our newsletter is if a person signs up themselves for the newsletter and provides their email to us for only that purpose. Any emails given to CarterMatt for the intended purpose of being part of our weekly newsletter will not be used for any other purpose, will not be shared, and will not be sold.

### GDPR Vendor List

[24]7.ai (successor to EngageClick)  
Adacado  
Adara Media  
AdClear  
ADEX  
Adform  
AdGear  
AdGibbon BV  
AdLedge  
Adloox  
Adnanny.com  
Adnetik  
Adnologies  
Adobe Advertising Cloud  
Adriver  
Adscale GmbH  
AdTriba  
advanced STORE GmbH  
Adventori  
adverServe  
Advolution.control  
Affilinet  
Akamai  
Amazon  
Amobee  
Anomaly  
Answer Media  
AppNexus  
Arrivalist  
AT Internet (Xiti)  
Audience2Media  
AudienceProject  
Awin  
Axparis.com  
Azameo  
Batch Media  
BDSK Handels GmbH & Co. KG  
Belboon  
Better Banners  
Bidswitch  
Bizible  
Bombora  
Brainworkz  
Broadband Enterprises  
C3 Metrics  
Cablato  
CDK Global  
Celtra  
Cheq  
Cint  
Clinch  
Cloud Technologies  
Cloudflare  
Cogo Labs  
Collective  
Commanders Act  
comScore  
Conversant/CJ Affiliate  
Conversion Logic  
Crimtan  
Criteo  
Datafy  
DataXu  
DMA Institute  
DoubleVerify  
Dynamic Yield  
Eacnur  
Ebuilders  
econda GmbH  
Effinity  
Emerse  
Ensighten  
Eulerian Technologies  
Evidon  
Exactag  
Exponential  
Eyereturn Marketing  
F Sharp  
Facebook  
Flashtalking  
FlxOne  
Fraudlogix  
Gemius  
GfK  
GlobalWebIndex  
Google  
GroupM  
Gskinner  
Haensel AMS  
Havas Media France – DBi  
Heathrow  
Heathrow Express  
Herolens  
Hostelworld.com Limited  
Hurra.com  
iBILLBOARD  
Ignition One  
Impact  
Index Exchange  
Infectious Media  
Infostrada  
Integral Ad Science  
intelliAd  
Isobar  
Jivox  
jQuery  
Jsdelivr  
Kantar  
KeyCDN  
Knorex  
Kwanzoo  
LiveRamp  
Lotame  
Macromill group  
Madison Logic  
Magnetic  
Markit  
MBR Targeting Gmbh  
MediaMath  
MEDIAN  
Meetrics  
Metalyzer  
MindTake Research  
Monotype Imaging, Inc.  
MSI-ACI  
MyFonts  
Naketano.de  
Nano Interactive  
NEORY GmbH  
netAFFILIATION  
Netflix  
Neuralone  
Neustar  
NEXD  
Nielsen  
Nordic Factory Solutions AB  
Norstat  
Numberly  
Oath  
OCM Internet  
OmniVirt  
OnAudience.com  
OneDigitalAd Technologies  
Oracle Data Cloud  
Parship  
Phaistos Networks  
Piximedia  
Platform161  
PopRule  
Publicis Groupe  
PubMatic  
Pulpo (An Entravision Company)  
Quantcast  
Rackspace  
Rakuten Marketing  
RAM  
Relay42  
RevJet  
RhythmOne LLC  
RN SSI Group  
Roq.ad  
Rubicon Project  
Salesforce DMP  
Scenestealer  
Scoota  
Semasio GmbH  
SFR  
Signal  
Sizmek  
Smart  
Sojern  
Spark Flow, SparkFlow  
Specific Media Inc.  
Speed Shift Media  
Swaven  
Taboola  
TACTIC™ Real-Time Marketing  
Tapad  
tapCLIQ  
Tealium  
Telegraph  
The Reach Group  
The Trade Desk  
Thunder  
TimeOne  
Tradedoubler  
travel audience – An Amadeus Company  
Travelers  
TripAdvisor  
TrustArc  
Turbobytes  
Twitter  
UDG  
usemax (Emego GmbH)  
Videology  
Vimeo  
Virtual Minds  
VIVALU  
Vorwerk  
Webgains  
Weborama  
White Ops  
Zanox  
ZMS  
Zuuvi
